

[MUHAMAD YUNUS]

Kuningan, Jawa Barat, 45587 | +628562034580 | halloyunus99@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/muhamad-yunus/ | https://github.com/halloyunus/

About Me

Hello, I'm Muhamad Yunus, currently I'm working as a regulatory reporting in the financial industry, I have experience -+ 2 years in the field regulatory reporting and experince in data analytic, web-based development and graphic design, and I am the 2nd best graduate of the information systems study program at Kuningan University, I have a very high career interest in regulatory reporting and information technology fields such as Analysts, Data Analysts, IT Analyst Systems, Data Science, but this does not rule out the possibility of working in other positions.

Ability & Competention

Tools : Python, SQL, Google Data Studio, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Acces, Macro VBA, Flask, HTML, CSS,

SoftSkill: Data Visualization, Data Preparation, Data Preperocessing, Analytical, Critical Thinking, Problem Solving, Communication, Design Thinking, Teamwork Ability, high willingness to learn, leadership, Easy adapt.

Experience

CIMB NIAGA Tbk

Regulatory Reporting Specialist (Feb 2024 - Present)

- Prepare and submit report to regulator on monthly (BI ANTASENA, SLIK OJK)
- Involved in automation project and development enhancement
- Checking anomaly data for reporting, analyze data resulting from internal or external audit
- Collaborate with other divisions in making reports and Support and analysis data for reportingz

MNC BANK INTERNATIONAL Tbk

Regulatory and Reporting Managament (January 2023 - Feb 2024)

- Prepare and submit report to regulator on daily, weekly, monthly, quarterly, semester and annual basis (BI ANTASENA, APOLO OJK)
- Involved in automation project and development enhancement
- Support Data for Management
- · Collaborate with other divisions in making reports

WEB DEVELOPMENT

Freelance Web Developmnet (Dec 2021 - June 2023)

Digital Skola - Digital Talent Development Program Data Science

Certified Independent Study Intern Data Science (Agu 2021 - Jan 2022)

- Completing role as data scientis in industry with real case study
- Implementing exploratory data analysis on online retail dataset and online donation dataset, implementing data preparationand processing data, implementing machine learning to classify data and compare few machine learning algorithm to get the best machine learning model.

ID/X Partners - Data, analytics & decisioning for profitability optimisation

Project-Based Intern Data Science (May 2022 - June 2022)

make a solution End to End for Business Acumen for Credit Risk Prediction
Credit risk prediction a potential risk of loss resulting from the failure by a borrower.
Credit risk prediction is an effective way of evaluating whether a potential borrower will repay a loan.

Home Credit Indonesia

Project-Based Intern Data Scientist (July 2022 - July 2022)

- Completing various tasks related to Data Scientist activities from Home Credit Indonesia, such as Exploratory Data Analys, Data Storytelling, Data Visualization, Machine Learning Modeling, and Business Acumen.
- Finding the best segmented customer to provide Marketing and Product Team with a better initial step for Product Launch
- · Machine Learning Modelling and Impact-Driven Business Insight for Home Credit Risk

Education

Kuningan University

S1 Information System - IPK 3,76 (Honors: Cumlaude)

 Final Project : Model Implementation of Data Mining in Prediciton Student Graduation Using K-Nearest Neighbor web-based information system

Course (February 2022 - Agustus 2022)

Data Science - DQLAB

Universiti Utara Malaysia

Student Exchange: B.Sc.IT (Hons), Bachelor of Science with Honours Infortmation Technology Course Focus on: Knowledge Dicovery in Database and Information Technology Management

Achivment

2nd Best Graduate of Kuningan University Information System 2022

Student Excahnge: School Computer Science, Universiti Uatara Malaysia (Mar 2021 - Agu 2021)

focus on: Knowledge Discovery in Database and Information Techonolgy Management

2nd Kuningan University Outstanding Student (2021)

Program Kretivitas Mahasiswa (KemendikbudRistek, 2021)

Kampus Mengajar 1 (KemendikbudRistek, 2021)

Computer Program Copyright (Minstry Of Law and Human Right Republic Indonesia, 2021)

• KP-spams water payment application web

Awardee Scholarship PAA 2019

3rd Winers Scientific Papers (National, 2017) Scientific Papers Competition FKIP UNIKU

Certification

Dicoding (Dicoding x Idcamp, 2023)

Data Science (Sololearn, 2022)

Data Science (KemendikbudRIstek, DigitalSkola, 2022)

Top 34 form 422 Challengers Financial Data Challange (BRI X BRIBRAIN X Sharing Vision, 2022)

Microcredential AI Certification Program For Associate Data Science (KemdikbudRistek, IARC, 2021)

IT Specialist-HTML5 Aplication Development (Certiport - A Pearson VUE Business, 2021)

Certified Junior Graphic Designer (BNSP, 2021)

Fundamental Machine Learning (Camp404, 2021)

Organization

BEM Fakultas Ilmu Komputer: Field Science and technology (Mar 2021 - Feb 2022)

• Developing technology training programs to improve human resources at BEM as well as being an event team for the computer science faculty festival event project which was attended by around 500+ people

Himpunan Mahasiswa Sistem Informasi: Field Media & Technology (2019 - 2021)

• Developing social media for information systems as well as being a training instructor for new students of information systems

Inspiring Generation

• This is related to social activities such as community service and sharing activities and I have also done sharing session experiences at high-achieving youth events